intouch.org 2018-12-28

# Privacy Policy

This is the web site of In Touch Ministries.   
Our postal address is:   
PO Box 7900   
Atlanta, GA 30357 

#### POLICY

At In Touch Ministries [ITM], our mission is to lead people worldwide into a growing relationship with Jesus Christ and to strengthen the local church.

ITM is a Christian ministry, organized as a Georgia non-profit corporation. The success of our mission requires that we daily earn your trust, by doing our utmost to preserve your privacy and the security of your personal information, and by clearly informing you of how we use your information. Thank you for taking the time to review the statements that follow. 

We continuously review our policies, procedures, and systems to make sure that we conform to the highest standards of information security, end-user transparency, and informed consent. This privacy policy may therefore change from time to time as circumstances warrant. When our privacy policy changes, the revised policy will be posted here. Please return to this page to view our current privacy policy. 

#### THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

##### NETWORK INFORMATION

Our systems automatically collect the IP address of the computer you use to visit our website, and track the number of site visitors and the number of visits to each page and resource on the website. This information cannot be used to identify a specific person. 

##### PERSONAL INFORMATION

ITM never collects personal information without your knowledge and consent. We may request personal information when you create an account, request a resource, create a subscription to one of our publications, make a donation, make a purchase, submit a prayer request, or use site links to otherwise communicate with us. This information may include, but may not be limited to, your first and last names, postal address, telephone number, email address, and other demographic information. For online transactions, we also request your credit card number, expiration date, and may request your Card Security Code [CSC, CVV2, or CCID] number. 

#### SMS subscriptions

Summary Terms & Conditions: Our mobile text messages are intended for subscribers over the age of 13 and are delivered via USA short code 99000 and 76000.You may receive up to 30 message(s) per month for text alerts. Message and data rates may apply. This service is available to persons with text-capable phones subscribing to carriers including AT&T, Verizon Wireless, T-Mobile®, Sprint, Virgin Mobile USA, Cincinnati Bell, Centennial Wireless, Unicel, U.S. Cellular®, and Boost. For help, text HELP to 99000, email partnerrelations@intouch.org, or call +1 8007891473. You may stop your mobile subscription at any time by text messaging STOP to short code 99000.

#### HOW WE USE THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We use network information to help us understand how people use our website, to administer the site, and to get trend-level information about site visitors and how they reached our site.

We use personal information primarily to serve your specific needs and fulfill your specific requests, at your personal direction. We may also share your personal information with external service providers who help us better serve you, under strict contractual terms that preserve your privacy and prevent any misuse of your personal information. Examples of such service providers include, but are not limited to, mailing service bureaus and credit card processors.

#### YOUR INFORMATION IS NEVER SOLD, RENTED, OR LEASED

Your use of our website is confidential. In Touch Ministries will not sell, rent, lease, or exchange your information with any other organization, except for those service providers who help us serve you under contract, as described in the preceding section of this policy, or if legally required to do so, such as by law, regulation, court order, subpoena, search warrant, or in response to privacy processes, or to protect the rights, property, or safety of In Touch Ministries or its personnel.

#### YOUR INFORMED CONSENT

By using our website, and by giving us your personal information, you agree that this Privacy Policy is part of the Terms of Use of this website, and you assent to this In Touch Ministries Privacy Policy. ITM reserves the right to change this policy at any time, without advance notice. Whenever we change our privacy policy, the revised policy will always be posted here for your review.

#### INFORMATION SECURITY AT ITM

ITM is committed to preserving the security of all information in our custody. Our information systems are maintained in physically secured, access-controlled data centers. All data are protected through a multi-layered approach at the network, storage, server, and applications levels, with data access rigorously controlled and limited to trained employees on a need-to-know basis. In addition, we engage external consultants to audit our online systems and test them periodically for all known vulnerabilities.

#### COOKIES

At our discretion, we may send a small file, commonly called a “cookie,” to your computer. Our Web servers use cookies to recognize you when you visit our site, and potentially to identify which areas or site features you have used. We may use cookies to personalize your online experience at our website. Cookies cannot damage your computer, nor can they read data from your hard drive.

You have the option, through changing your browser settings, of refusing all cookies, or of being notified when a website attempts to send a cookie to your browser. If you choose not to accept cookies, your online experience may be restricted, and some site features may not operate as designed.

#### SECURE CREDIT CARD PROCESSING

ITM uses Secure Sockets Layer [SSL] technology to securely encrypt data sent during credit card transactions. Credit card numbers are not retained on our online systems, but are immediately destroyed once passed to our credit card processor. You can be confident that your online transactions with In Touch Ministries are secured to the highest standards set by the credit card processing industry.

#### CHILDREN’S POLICY

In Touch Ministries will not knowingly collect or preserve data from children under 16 years of age. We recommend that you become involved with your child’s Internet activities and their access to our site, so that you can help protect their privacy. We recommend the article “Protecting Kids’ Privacy” at the Federal Trade Commission website and the [ProtectKids.com](http://www.protectkids.com/) website as resources you can use to help protect your children.

#### OBTAINING, VIEWING AND CHANGING YOUR INFORMATION

Upon request we will provide you with access to all information, including proprietary information, that we maintain about you, including unique identifier information (for example, your customer number and/or password), transaction information (for example, dates on which you made donations and/or purchases, and amounts and types of your donations and/or purchases), communications that you have directed to our site (for example, e-mails and other inquiries), your contact information (for example, your name, address, and telephone number), and a description of any other information we may maintain about you.

You can obtain this information by writing to us at:

In Touch Ministries  
PO Box 7900  
Atlanta, GA 30357 

We can also be reached via e-mail at [partnerrelations@intouch.org](mailto:partnerrelations@intouch.org), or you can reach us by calling our Customer Care Center toll-free at 800.789.1473. (Hours M-F 8:00 am - 7:00 pm) 

Please feel free at any time to request correction of any inaccuracies in your contact information and unique identifiers. You may request corrections by sending us e-mail at the above address, calling us at the above telephone number, or writing to us at the above address. 

You can view and change much of your account information by logging in to the In Touch website at http://www.intouch.org, then clicking the “My Account” link. 

#### OPTING OUT

Our goal is to serve you with excellence. We never intend to send communications you do not want.

If you do not want to receive email from us in the future, please let us know by unsubscribing as indicated in the email, sending us email at the above address, calling us at the above telephone number, or writing to us at the above address.

If you supply us with your postal address online you may receive periodic mailings from us, with information about new resources and services or upcoming events. If you do not wish to receive such mailings, please let us know by calling us at the number provided above, emailing us at the above address, or writing to us at the above address. 

If you give us your telephone number(s) online, you may receive telephone calls from us, with information about new resources and services or upcoming events. If you do not wish to receive such telephone calls, please let us know by sending us e-mail at the above address, calling us at the above telephone number, or writing to us at the above address. 

#### FURTHER QUESTIONS

If you have any further questions about In Touch Ministries' privacy policy, please contact us. Thank you for visiting our website!
